Ranjan Lamichhane

lamichhanera @warhawks.ulm.edu (214) 606-7370 www.linkedin.com/in/ranjanlamichhane-2699aa272/

SUMMARY

A full stack web developer with 2 years of experience creating web applications, deploying and maintaining them. Possess utmost knowledge of React.js, Express.js and MongoDB along with Vanilla JavaScript. Looking to leverage my knowledge and experience into an internship role as Full Stack Web Developer.

SKILLS

- MERN stack
- Typescript
- Next.js
- AWS (EC2 / S3 / Elastic Beanstalk/ Amplify)
- Communication and Collaboration with team
- Project Management

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF LOUSIANA MONROE

August 2024

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Minor: Mathematics

• Presidential Distinguished Scholarship, 4.0 GPA

EXPERIENCE

OTS Academy-Oxford, United Kingdom

Feb 2024- Aug 2024

Remote Full Stack Web Developer

- Developed a full-fledged website of the Academy using Next.js and Typescript.
- Worked with project manager to understand the objective and design of the website.
- Learned new techs like ubuntu, AWS and Prisma ORM which were required for the project.

Shrestha Ventures- Kathmandu, Nepal

Jun 2023- Feb 2024

Remote Full Stack Web Developer

- Developed backend architecture of websites on Node.js and performed CRUD operations on MongoDB.
- Developed front-end part of websites using React.js / Vanilla JavaScript.
- Fixed various bugs in the existing and pending projects and improvised the security and authentication.
- Led two interns (each of backend and frontend) to create fully functional websites.
- Worked with graphic designer and supervisor to reduce friction during development and planning process.

LEADERSHIP AND COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

ICT Club, President, Pokhara, Nepal

Jun 2022- Feb 2023

- Solving queries of peers about the job environment and guiding them to create a good portfolio
- Working closely with board members to organize various events like Hackathon, Coding competitions, etc.

Org45, Contributor and Trainer, Kathmandu, Nepal

- Providing online seminars to aspiring react developers
- Contributing to the open source projects of the organization.